<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">RetroGames</string>
    <color name="white">#FFFFFF</color>

    <string name="games_tab">Games</string>
    <string name="stats_tab">Statistics</string>
    <string name="hist_tab">History</string>
    <string name="settings_tab">Settings</string>
    <string name="pong_tab">Pong</string>
    <string name="si_tab">Space Invaders</string>

    <string name="general_settings">General</string>
    <string name="level">Game level</string>
    <string name="easy">Easy</string>
    <string name="medium">Medium</string>
    <string name="hard">Hard</string>
    <string name="about_p">About Pong</string>
    <string name="number">Number of balls</string>
    <string name="sudden">Sudden direction change</string>
    <string name="about_i">About Space Invaders</string>
    <string name="shooting">Invaders are shooting us!</string>
    <string name="invader">Now you\'re the invader</string>
    <string-array name="number_balls">
        <item>1</item>
        <item>2</item>
        <item>3</item>
    </string-array>
    
    <string name="eol">&lt;br />&lt;br /></string>
    
    <string name="first_pong">
        Pong (marketed as PONG) is one of the earliest arcade video games, 
        and is a tennis sports game featuring simple two-dimensional graphics. 
        The game was originally manufactured by Atari Incorporated (Atari), who 
        released it in 1972. &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Allan_Alcorn">Allan Alcorn&lt;/a>
        created Pong as a training exercise assigned to him by Atari co-founder 
        &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nolan_Bushnell">Nolan Bushnell&lt;/a>. 
        Bushnell based the idea on an electronic ping-pong game included in the 
        &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Magnavox_Odyssey">Magnavox Odyssey&lt;/a>, 
        which later resulted in a lawsuit against Atari.
    </string>
    
    <string name="second_pong">
        After diving into the design of the Magnavox version, Alcorn went on to create his own design
        based on hi knowledge of transistor-transistor logic. Feeling the original Magnavox\'s game was
        too boring, Alcorn added features to give the game more appeal. He divided the paddle into eight segments 
        to change the ball\'s angle of return. He also made the ball accelerate the more it was returned back 
        and forth between paddles; missing the ball reset the speed. Another feature was that the in-game paddles 
        were unable to reach the top of screen. This was caused by a simple circuit that had an inherent defect. 
        Instead of dedicating time to fixing the defect, Alcorn decided it gave the game more difficulty and 
        helped limit the time the game could be played.
    </string>
    
    <string name="third_pong">
        After months of development, Alcorn finally assembled a prototype of the game. In September 1972, Bushnell 
        and Alcorn installed the Pong prototype at a local bar, Andy Capp\'s Tavern. Bushnell and Alcorn placed the 
        prototype on one of the tables near the other entertainment machines: a jukebox, pinball machines, and Computer Space.
        The game was well received the first night and its popularity continued to grow over the next one and a 
        half weeks. Bushnell then went on a business trip to Chicago. A few days later, the prototype began 
        exhibiting complications and Gattis contacted Alcorn to fix it. Upon inspecting the machine, Alcorn 
        discovered the mechanisms had jammed from an overflow of quarters.
    </string>
    
    <string name="last_pong">
        For further information, please the wiki page: &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pong">Pong&lt;/a>.
    </string>
</resources>
